What would happen if the moon exploded?
Would tides disappear? Would big chunks
rain down on Earth? Okay, let's blow it
up. You're going to need a very big
explosion to get the job done because
otherwise you just crack it apart and
then the moon's gravity would go blub.
So, you need to send 600 billion of the
largest nuclear bombs ever built. With
that size explosion, bad news, most of
the chunks will fall to Earth. But good
news, most would probably burn up in our
atmosphere. But bad news, all that
burning up would create a lot of heat.
So much that we'd get cooked. Assuming
that we could survive that, good news,
tides still exist, but they'd be less
than half of what we're used to, pulled
only by the sun. Good news, maybe, the
Earth would get rings, but bad news,
we'd start wobbling. We need the moon to
stabilize Earth's tilt. But most people
don't understand just how far away the
moon actually is. To see [music] that,
subscribe.